Contact

Palestine-Gaza 0598530950 (Mobile) aliabuharb8530@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ali-abu-harb (LinkedIn) github.com/alex8530 (Other)

Top Skills

Android
Back-End Web Development
Networking

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Google Certified Android Developer-Advanced Android Nanodegree Certified From Udacity

Honors-Awards

The First Winner in Hackathone that was to help women who suffer from cancer in Gaza Sky Geeks and got 1000\$

Ali Abu Harb

Google Certified Android Developer & Back-End web Developer Palestinian Territory

Summary

Hi, I am a Computer Engineer and an Android developer with extensive experience in various Google technologies, 3rd party libraries and integration products. worked with agile methodologies, several Android and Java courses.

I am familiar with web frameworks back-end development ASP.NET MVC 5 And Core, in addition with Laravel framework, web api services.

Specialties:

✓ Native Android development, experienced in Object Oriented Design and Android Design Patterns

- √ Working with Model–View–ViewModel (MVVM), a software architectural pattern
- ✓ Communicating design options in a non-technical way with a focus
 on ease of use and simplicity
- ✓ Proficient with all aspects of software development from design to release using Agile methodology
- √ Working with chained Git repositories (submodules) and complex Gradle projects
- √ Working with back-end web frameworks such as Laravel & ASP.NET
- √Building Restful API

Skills:

- ✓ Languages: Java, JavaScript, C#, PHP, HTML, CSS
- ✓ IDEs: IntelliJ, Android Studio, Visual Studio, PHPStorm
- ✓ Version Control System: Git (GitHub, Bitbucket, Phabricator)
- ✓ Data persistency: SQLite, ORM, Realm, Room

✓ Android libraries: Dagger2, RxJava, Picasso, Glide, retrofit2, ButterKnife, UI Test (UIAutomater and Espresso), Unit Test (Junit and Mockito), Firebase, Api

Experience

Gaza Sky Geeks

Member in GeeXelerator Program at Gaza Sky Geeks

April 2019 - Present

Palestinian Territory

Join with my team in GeeXelerator Program at Gaza Sky Geeks, so our idea is accepted to participate in this program

Palestine information and communications technology incubator (picti)

Back End Developer (ASP MVC 5) Trainee

January 2019 - Present

Gaza

Palestine Telecommunications (Paltel) Group Android Developer Trainee July 2018 - Present Palestinian Territory

I meet a lot of people who work for companies like Facebook and Google. I have training on Version Control and Android development in advanced topics with complex Problem Solving techniques.

What has been accomplished:

►Worked on a large project and learned how to cooperate with others through Version Control

like Git with GitHub

- ►Worked on a lot of problem solving
- ► Learned advanced topics in Android

Deepcoders Network Trainee July 2018 - August 2018 (2 months) Gaza The training consisted of all types of systems including Windows Server and Linux administration. We set up a network that connected and controlled a set of devices within the network.

We dealt with Windows Server, created users and controlling them; created a group of companies and a group of branches; connected them and gave each branch different privacy settings; shared files and controlled the branches through Windows Server. We also dealt with the Linux system and the addition and control of groups and people.

What has been accomplished:

►Worked on big project that manage a lot of users and make network between them,give privileges

and share files using Windows Server

►The same thing worked on top but using Linux

Gaza Sky Geeks
Graduate from the Freelancer Academy
May 2018 - July 2018 (3 months)

Palestinian Territory

Join with Freelance Academy-4 at Gaza Sky Geeks

Education

Udacity

Android Nanodegree program · (2018 - 2019)

Islamic University - Gaza
Bachelor's degree Computer Engineering at IUG with
GPA(88%) · (2014 - 2019)